Inventory of the Clarissa Sligh Papers, 1950-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2012-0149),1985-2012, (35 boxes)
  This accession was acquired in 2012. It documents the artists' work and process and includes photographs and negatives, large screen prints, and political posters. Photographic prints are mainly portraits. Sligh's original order has been preserved, and her own descriptions were used whenever possible.
  - Judy Wesalo-Temel (Box 81)
  - Mississippi is America (Box 81)
  - Nancy Millar, 1985-86 (Box 81)
  - Malcolm X and Civil Rights (Box 81)
  - Lucy Lippard's Picnic, 1985 (Box 81)
  - Loft Interior, 465 West Broadway (Box 81)
  - Linda Wood-Hoyte, 1998 (Box 81)
  - Linda Thompson Portrait (Box 81)
  - Guerilla Girls (Box 81)
  - September 11 Anniversary (Box 81)
  - Aaron Roseman with Stop US Intervention Banner (Box 81)
  - Aaron Roseman Assorted Photos (Box 81)
  - Air Baraka Birthday (Box 81)
  - Annie Shaver-Crandell, 1986 (Box 81)
  - Antaures (Box 81)
  - Barbara Sauer (Box 81)
  - Carole Byard (Box 81)
  - Constance Agnus (Box 81)
  - Donna Prince (Box 81)
  - E.Frances White (Box 81)
  - Ethel Hultberg (Box 81)
  - Faith Ringgold and Camille Billops, 1988 (Box 81)
  - Hettie Jones, 1986 (Box 81)
  - Howardena Pindell Portrait (Box 81)
  - Irene Elmore (Box 81)
  - Jodie Olsen Wedding, 2003 (Box 81)
  - John and Selina Randolph (Box 81)
  - Reading Dick and Jane With Me Project Development (Box 82)
  - Reading Dick and Jane With Me Notes (Box 82)
  - Relationships Ex. Label, 1991 (Box 82)
  - Reunion, 1991 (Box 82)
  - Reunion Installation Project (Box 82)
  - Witness Project, 1992 (Box 82)
  - Suburban Atlanta, 1994-Parts 1-7 (Box 82)
  - Brother's Keeper (Box 82)
  - Masculinity Project: Jeff Hill (Box 82)
  - Jeff Hill at Schaefer's Soccer (Box 82)
  - Masculinity Project
    - James in Library and Erik with Amy (Box 82)
    - Henry Matthews (Box 82)
    - Eddie Dixon (Box 82)
    - Charles Ridens, 1996 (Box 82)
    - Chris Staley (Box 82)
    - Barbara Mora and Rachel (Box 82)
    - Jesse and Omar, Dallas, TX (Box 82)
    - Joe Saunders (Box 82)
    - John Blundred (Box 82)
    - John El Badn, Union Temple Church, Washington, D.C. (Box 82)
    - Luke Chen at TWU (Box 82)
    - Maxwell Hasson-Texas with Guitar (Box 83)
    - Perry (Box 83)
    - Philip Brookman (Box 83)
    - Richard Klein (Box 83)
    - Rick Dingus (Box 83)
    - Robert Stewart (Box 83)
    - Roger Boykin (Box 83)
    - Sylvester Johnson (Box 83)
    - Wilson Meador with Daryl and Cody (Box 83)
  - Clarissa Sligh and Aaron Roseman (Box 83)
  - Clarissa Sligh and Sheila Grands (Box 83)
  - Michael Roseman (Box 83)
  - Nancy Spero Visit (Box 83)
  - NYC
    - Brooklyn Bridge (Box 83)
    - Canal Street (Box 83)
    - Central Park (Box 83)
    - Christo and Central Park (Box 83)
    - Jones Beach (Box 83)
    - Lower East Side (Box 83)
    - Lower East Side: 3 Teens Kill 4 Band, 1984 (Box 83)
    - Lower Manhattan (Box 83)
    - Lower Manhattan, 2011 (Box 83)
    - Midtown (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 83)
    - Soho, 1979-81 (Box 83)
    - Soho: Here is New York, 2001 (Box 83)
    - Soho, Homeless Man, 1979 (Box 83)
    - Soho Village, 2002 (Box 83)
    - Soho and West Broadway, 2001 (Box 83)
    - Wall Street, 1980-81 (Box 84)
    - Union Square Park Labor Day Parade, 1981 (Box 84)
    - Street Art of New York, 1984 (Box 84)
    - Wall Street Selections (Box 84)
    - Waterside Plaza, 1977-78 (Box 84)
    - World Trade Center and Statue of Liberty, 1977 (Box 84)
    - World Trade Center Collapse, September 11, 2001 (shot from West Broadway) (Box 84)
    - West Village after 9/11 (Box 84)
    - World Trade Center Site, 2002 (Box 84)
  - Newark, NJ, 1987 (Box 84)
  - Nexus Press Residency, Atlanta, 1998 (Box 84)
  - Paris (includes Shelley and Tommy Rice) (Box 84)
  - Paul Hultburg (Box 84)
  - Penland, 1994 (includes Toronto Installation) (Box 84)
  - Penland, 2000 (Box 84)
  - Penland, 2005 (Box 84)
  - Penland, Summer 2007 (Box 84)
  - Places-TX, Washington D.C., NYC, NM (Box 85)
  - Ravenna Narizzano (Box 85)
  - Salynn McCollum (Gramercy Day Care Center) (Box 85)
  - Salynn McCollum and Day Care Staff (Gramercy) (Box 85)
  - Salynn and John in New Mexico, 1991 (Box 85)
  - Salynn McCollum (Box 85)
  - Self Portraits- Texas on Javier Luzano's Motorcycle (Box 85)
  - Self Portraits for "Who She Was" Collage (Box 85)
  - Self Portraits for Politics of Gender Catalog (Box 85)
  - Seline Okuyan, Tim Swonder, and Koray, April 20, 2003 (Box 85)
  - Self-Portraits for "She Sucked Her Thumb" (Box 85)
  - Susan Crowe with Sculpture and Manhattan Skyline from under Brooklyn Bridge, 1994 (Box 85)
  - Tammy with NYC friends (Box 85)
  - Texas-Other Shots (Box 85)
  - TWU-Smith Carroll Abandoned Building (Box 85)
  - VCCA Residency, August 2000 (Box 85)
  - VSW Residency, 2005 (Box 85)
  - WCA Conference Prep, NYC, 1986 (Box 85)
  - WCA Fundraiser, 1985 (Box 85)
  - West Indian Parade, Brooklyn (Box 85)
  - Willie Portrait (Box 85)
  - What's Happening With Momma? Artist's Book Work (Box 85)
  - Aaron Roseman-Other Artist's Materials (photos of his work) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Other Artist's Materials (kids drawings) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Other Artist's Materials (correspondence) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Other Artist's Materials (catalogs) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Other Artist's Materials (articles) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Portraits, Slides and Prints (documentation) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Drawings, Prints and Paintings (slides) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Drawings, Prints and Paintings (prints) (Box 86)
  - Aaron Roseman-Avenue of the Americas (Box 86)
  - Political Posters, 1983 (Box 86)
  - Washington Square Park, Art Demonstration, 2003 (Box 87)
  - Political Posters on Soho Streets (Box 87)
  - Demonstration Against US Intervention in Central America, Peoples' Monument, Washington D.C., 1983 (Box 87)
  - NYC Political Rallies-U.N. Park (includes Banners from Avenue of Americas) (Box 87)
  - MOMA, NYC: Women Artists Visibility Event, 1984 (the MOMA opens, but not to women artists) (Box 87)
  - March on Washington, April 1985 (Box 87)
  - Central Park Peace Rally (Box 87)
  - Artists Call Against US Intervention in Central America-Avenue for Americas (Xeroxes for films) (Box 87)
  - Artists Call Against US Intervention in Central America-Times Square Rally, 1984 (Box 87)
  - Artists Call Against US Intervention in Central America-The Peoples' Monument, 1983 (Box 87)
  - Artists Call Against US Intervention in Central America-Avenue of the Americans, January 1984 (Box 87)
  - Aaron Roseman-Snapshots (Box 87)
  - Aaron Roseman-Research Materials (including Nicaragua) (Box 87)
  - Aaron Roseman-Political Demonstrations (includes slides) (Box 87)
  - Aaron Roseman-Other Artist's Materials (photos of Aaron and passport) (Box 87)
  - Aaron Roseman-Scripts of Plays with Amiri Baraka, "What is the Relationship of the Lone Ranger to the Means of Production?" (Box 87)
  - Aaron Roseman-Scripts of Plays with Amiri Baraka, "The Motion of History" (Box 87)
  - Aaron Roseman-Research Materials (Box 87)
  - Documentation of Art works, Part 1
    - Mississippi is America (documentation slides) (Box 88)
    - Jake in Transition (documentation slides and CD-Rom) (Box 88)
    - It Wasn't Little Rock, 2004 (Hand-bound book and slides) (Box 88)
    - Hiroshima Book (slides) (Box 88)
    - Linda Wood Hoyte-Body-Builder (slides) (Box 88)
    - Suburban Atlanta Series (documentation slides) (Box 88)
    - Atlanta Exposition Installation-Searching for Memories, 1995 (Box 88)
    - Assurance of Silence (Box 88)
    - All Your Life (Box 88)
    - ABC Columbus Project (Box 88)
    - Home-Silkscreen, 1987 (not image-text) (Box 88)
    - Handmade Paper Prints, Riverdale, MD (Helen Frederick, Director) (Box 88)
    - Family Photos Used for Artwork (Box 88)
    - Early Work-Miscellaneous (Box 88)
    - Collaborative Sketchbooks with Nancy Chalker-Tennant (Box 88)
    - Coast to Coast Women Artists Book Project- Lisa Yee, Kim Chee and Rice, Faith Ringgold and Lisa Yee- Collaborative Quilt Book (Box 88)
    - Coast to Coast Women Artists Book Project and Guerilla Girl-Exhibition in Houston, TX (Box 88)
    - Coast to Coast Box Project, 1991 (Box 88)
    - Malcolm X (Box 88)
  - Documentation of Artworks, Part 2
    - Run (slides) (Box 89)
    - Richmond Church, 1999 (prints and slides) (Box 89)
    - Reunion- Work in Progress (slides) (Box 89)
    - Reunion (slides, Part 1) (Box 89)
    - Reunion, NC (slides, Part 2) (Box 89)
    - Reunion (notes) (Box 89)
    - Relationships (contact sheet and slides) (Box 89)
    - Reframing the Past (prints) (Box 89)
    - Red Dress (slides and prints) (Box 89)
    - Reading Dick and Jane With Me-Pages (slides and transparencies) (Box 89)
    - Reading Dick and Jane With Me-Artist's Book (contact sheet) (Box 89)
    - Reading Dick and Jane With Me (slides and transparencies) (Box 89)
    - Passages Installation-Snug Harbor, Staten Island, NY (slides) (Box 89)
    - Sandy Ground (duplicates) (Box 90)
    - Sandy Ground (slides) (Box 90)
    - Sandy Ground (more slides and prints) (Box 90)
    - Sandy Ground (contact sheet) (Box 90)
    - Skookie (Box 90)
    - Slept (prints and slides) (Box 90)
    - Stamps, 1939 (Box 90)
    - Sucked Her Thumb (Box 90)
    - She Sucked Her Thumb and Devastated (Box 90)
    - She Sucked Her Thumb (large prints) and Halloween in Syracuse (Box 90)
    - Temptation of Eve Revisited (Box 90)
    - Time is Money Collage, 1981 (Box 90)
    - Trier, German Exhibition (Box 90)
    - Untitled (for Momma), 2002 (Box 90)
    - Voyager Artist's Book (Box 90)
    - Waiting for Daddy (Box 90)
    - Waiting for Daddy, Skookie, and She Didn't Know Who She Was (contact sheet) (Box 90)
    - Wall Street-Vicious Circle, 1986 (Box 90)
    - Wall Street-Vicious Cycle and Home Project(s) (Box 90)
  - Documentation of Artworks, Part 3
    - What's Happening With Momma? (Book Dummy 1), Cherry Blossoms, and Who She Was (Box 91)
    - What's Happening With Momma? (book in print installation) (Box 91)
    - What's Happening With Momma? (silk screen and letterpress) (Box 91)
    - What's Happening With Momma? (Van Dyke brown print) (Box 91)
    - What's Happening With Momma? (visual poem) (Box 91)
    - Who She Was (slides) (Box 91)
    - Who She Was (slides of print installation) (Box 91)
    - Witness Project-AIG Installation, March 8, 1992 (Box 91)
    - Witness Project-Art in General (Box 91)
    - Witness Project-Carleton College (Box 91)
    - Witness Project-Washington Project for the Arts (WPA) (Box 91)
    - Women Bring the People (Box 91)
    - Wonderful Uncle (Box 91)
  - Documentation of Artworks, Part 4
    - Wrongly Bodied Two (artist's book) (Box 92)
    - Wrongly Bodied Two (artist's book, work-in-progress) (Box 92)
    - Jake Family Photos (Box 92)
    - Jake Project Sketches (Box 92)
    - Jake in Transition-Part 1-3 (Box 92)
  - Documentation of Artworks, Part 5
    - Masculinity Project: Parts 1-3 (Box 93)
    - Masculinity Project (extra slides) (Box 93)
    - MFA Thesis Exhibition, Howard University, 1999 (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous Documentation (Box 93)
    - Moonmade Space Installation, 1984 (Box 93)
    - Paintings, 1969-70 (includes time in Ethiopia) (Box 93)
    - Quakertown, Denton, TX, 1997 (Box 93)
    - Self-Portrait Drawings (Box 93)
  - Documentation of Artworks, Part 6
    - Jake in Transition, Part 4 (Box 94)
    - Jake in Transition, Part 5 (Box 94)
    - Self-Portraits (slides and prints) (Box 94)
    - Show He Can-School Paintings, 1972 (Box 94)
    - Rocky Mount, NC (Box 94)
    - TWU-Visual Art Work, 1995-97 (Box 94)
    - Untitled (painted book, work-in-progress) (Box 94)
    - VCCA Resident, December 2001 (Drawings/Sketches for Books) (Box 94)
    - Window and Doorway, 1987 (Box 94)
  - Photonegatives, Part 1
    - Amiri Baraka's Birthday (Box 95)
    - Annie Shaver-Crandell, 1986 (Box 95)
    - Antaures (Box 95)
    - Barbara Sauer (Box 95)
    - Carole Byard (Box 95)
    - E. Frances White (Box 95)
    - Judy Wesalo-Temel (Box 95)
    - John and Selina Randolph (Box 95)
    - Faith Ringgold and Camille Billops, 1988 (Box 95)
    - Linda Wood-Hoyte, 1998 (Box 95)
    - Loft Interior, 645 West Broadway (Box 95)
    - Lucy Lippard's Picnic, 1985 (Box 95)
    - Malcolm X and Civil Rights (Box 95)
    - Nancy Millar, 1985-86 (Box 95)
    - Suburban Atlanta, 1994-Parts 1-6 (Box 95)
    - Suburban Atlanta, 1994-Part 2 of 6 (Box 95)
    - Reunion, 1991 (Box 95)
    - Brother's Keeper (Box 95)
    - Masculinity Project
      - Masculinity Project: Barbara Mora and Rachel (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Charles Ridens, 1996 (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Chris Staley (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Eddie Dixon (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Henry Matthews (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: James in Library and Erik with Amy (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Jeff Hill (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Jeff Hill a Schaefer's Soccer (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: German Perez, Phoenix Apartments (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Jesse and Omar, Dallas, TX (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Joe Saunders (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: John Blundred (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: John El Badn, Union Temple Church, Washington D.C. (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Luke Chen at TWU (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Maxwell Hasson with guitar, TX (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Perry (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Philip Brookman (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Richard Klein (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Rick Dingus (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Robert Stewart (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Roger Boykin (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Sylvester Johnson (Box 95)
      - Masculinity Project: Wilson Meador with Daryl and Cody (Box 95)
    - Clarissa Sligh and Sheila Grands (Box 95)
    - Michael Roseman (Box 95)
    - Nancy Spero Visit (Box 95)
    - NYC-Lower East side, 3 Teens Kill 4 Band, 1984 (Box 95)
  - Photo Negatives, Part 2
    - NYC-Soho: Here is New York, 2001 (Box 96)
    - NYC-Soho, Homeless Man, 1979 (Box 96)
    - NYC-Soho/Village, 2002 (Box 96)
    - NYC-Wall Street, 1980-81 (Box 96)
    - NYC-West Side Pier (Box 96)
    - NYC-World Trade Center Site, 2002 (Box 96)
    - Newark, NJ, 1987 (Box 96)
    - Paris (including Shelley and Tommy Rice) (Box 96)
    - Penland, 1994 (includes Toronto Installation) (Box 96)
    - Penland, 2005 (Box 96)
    - Places- TX, NYC, Washington D.C., NM (Box 96)
    - Ravenna Narizzano (Box 96)
    - Salynn McCollum and Day Care Staff (Box 96)
    - Salynn McCollum, Gramercy Day Care Center, Bronx, NYC (Box 96)
    - Salynn and John in New Mexico, 1991 (Box 96)
    - Salynn McCollum (Box 96)
    - Self-Portraits- Pictures on Javier Luzano's Motorcycle (Box 96)
    - Self-Portraits for Politics of Gender Catalog (Box 96)
    - Self-Portraits for She Sucked Her Thumb (Box 96)
    - Self-Portraits for "Who She Was" Collage (Box 96)
    - Selime Okuyan and family, April 20, 2003 (Box 96)
    - Susan Crowe with Sculpture and Manhattan Skyline, 1994 (Box 96)
    - Tammy with NYC Friends (Box 96)
    - TWU-Smith Carroll Abandoned Building (Box 96)
    - WCA Conference Prep, NYC, 1986 (Box 96)
    - WCA Fundraiser, 1985 (Box 96)
    - Willie Portrait (Box 96)
    - What's Happening With Momma? (Artist's book) (Box 96)
    - Faith Ringgold- Quilt Exhibition, 1988 (Box 96)
    - Aaron Roseman- Avenue of the Americas (Box 96)
    - Aaron Roseman- Other Artist's Materials (Box 96)
    - Aaron Roseman- Drawings, Prints, and Paintings (Box 96)
    - Aaron Roseman- Political Demonstrations (Box 96)
    - Aaron Roseman- Snapshots (Box 96)
    - Aaron Roseman, Goldsboro, NC (Box 96)
  - Photo Negatives, Part 3
    - "The Collector", Paul R. Jones (Box 97)
    - Early Work- Miscellaneous (Box 97)
    - Collaborative Sketchbooks with Nancy Chalker-Tennant (Box 97)
    - Coast to Coast Women of Color Artist's Book Project and Guerilla Girl Installation (restricted) (Box 97)
    - Coast to Coast Box Project, 1991 (Box 97)
    - Artist's Call Against US Intervention in Central America, Avenue of the Americas, January 1984 (Box 97)
    - Mississippi is America- Documentation (Box 97)
    - Reading Dick and Jane With Me (Artist's Book) (Box 97)
    - Relationships (Box 97)
    - Reunion (Box 97)
    - Richmond Church, 1999 (Box 97)
    - Sandy Ground (transparencies) (Box 97)
    - Sucked Her Thumb (transparencies and negatives) (Box 97)
    - She Sucked Her Thumb and Devastated (Box 97)
    - She Sucked Her Thumb and Halloween in Syracuse (Box 97)
    - Temptation of Eve Revisited (Box 97)
    - Trier, Germany Exhibition (Box 97)
    - Untitled (for Momma), 2002 (Box 97)
    - Waiting for Daddy, Skookie, and She Didn't Know Who She Was (Box 97)
    - Wall Street-Vicious Cycle and Home Project (Box 97)
    - What's Happening With Momma?, Cherry Blossoms, and Who She Was (Box 97)
    - What's Happening With Momma? (Van Dyke brown printing) (Box 97)
    - Witness Project, AIG Installation, March 8, 1992 (Box 97)
    - Witness Project, WPA Installation (Box 97)
    - MFA Thesis Explanation, Howard University, 1999 (Box 97)
    - Miscellaneous Documentation (Box 97)
    - Moonmade Space Installation, 1984 (Box 97)
    - Self-Portraits (Box 97)
    - TWU- Visual Art Work, 1995-97 (Box 97)
    - Jake in Transition (Box 97)
    - Rata Lac and Diane Moonmade-Cafe in Soho (Box 97)
    - Exhibition Opening at VSW with Nancy Chalker-Tennant (Box 97)
    - Photos of Sligh (Box 97)
    - Ellen Eisenman Portraits (Box 97)
    - Deb Photographing Sligh in Arlington (Box 97)
  - Art Journals
    - C.E.P.A. Quarterly, vol. 2 no.2, Winter 1987: The Pleasures of Childhood; p.13 (Box 98)
    - C.E.P.A., vol. 13 no. 2, Winter/Spring 1988: Advertisement of Curator's Choice (Box 98)
    - After Image, vol.17 no. 5, December 1989: "Reinscribing the Self: An Interview with Clarissa Sligh"; p. 6-9 (Box 98)
    - Nueva Luz, vol.3 no. 2, 1990: Features "She Sucked Her Thumb," "Wonderful Uncle," "When They Played House," "Reframing the Past," "Skookie," "Waiting for Daddy," "Goldmine," "Cousin Gail's House," and "Steps" as well as commentary; p.22-31. (Box 98)
    - Contact Sheet, no. 112, 2001: Features "Jake in Transition"; pps. 10-16 (Box 98)
    - Contact Sheet, no. 97, 1998 (25th Anniversary Edition): Features "Spot Played, Dick Played with Spot"; p. 55 (Box 98)
    - Black Renaissance Noir, vol. 5, no. 1, Spring 2003; Cover Art (Box 98)
    - Art Journal, vol. 50, no. 2, Summer 1991 (Feminist Art Criticism): "Where's the Artist? Feminist Practice and Postructural Theories of Authorship" by Linda S. Clinger; pps. 39-47 (Box 98)
    - Photography, no. 50 (It's All Relative); "Healing the Cultural Body: Clarissa Sligh's Unfinished Business" by Laura U Marks; pps. 18-27 (Box 98)
    - Contact Sheet, no. 67; Features "Wonderful Uncle," "Home,"and "I Sucked My Thumb" (Box 98)
    - Exposure: Race, Photography, and American Culture, vol. 33, no. 1/2, 2000: "Brown Crayons and Black Dolls: the Art of Coming of Age" by Lisa Gail Collins; pps. 43-52 (Box 98)
    - Exposure, vol. 41, no. 1, Spring 2009: "Clarissa Sligh and Zanele Muholi in Conversation" with Carla Williams; pps. 4-17 (Box 98)
    - Fireweed Language, no. 44/45, Summer 1994 (A Feminist Quarterly of Writing, Politics, Art, and Culture): Letter calling for written reflections, p. 122 (Box 98)
    - Hayden's Ferry Review, no. 36, Spring/Summer 2005: "Jake in Transition"; pps. 79-81 (Box 98)
    - Heresies, no. 20 (A Feminist Publication on Art and Politics): Untitled, p. 30 (Box 98)
    - Heresies, no. 21 (Food is a Feminist Issue): "Nuclear Food" by Clarissa Sligh; pps.78-79 (Box 98)
    - Heresies, vol. 6, no. 24 (12 Years): "Fun with Dick and Jane"; p. 89 (Box 98)
    - Heresies, vol. 7, no.1, issue. 25 (The Art of Education): "On Being An American Black Student" by Clarissa Sligh; pps 29-33 (Box 98)
    - Ikon (Focus on Autobiography and Short Fiction), issue. 10 (Anniversary Edition): Clarissa Sligh: Photographs, pps. 57-59 (Box 98)
    - Ikon, issue 12/13 (The Nineties: Moving Forward and Reaching Back/ A Mulicultural Odyssey): "Waters of Dissent: It Wasn't Little Rock" by Clarissa Sligh, pps. 110-115 (Box 98)
    - Image, vol. 38, no. 3-4: "Reading Deeper: The Legacy of Dick and Jane in the work of Clarissa Sligh" by Carla Williams, pps. 3-16 (Box 98)
    - The International Review of African American Art, vol. 8, no. 4: "What's Happening With Momma?"; p. 17 (Box 98)
    - The International Review of African American Art, vol. 14, no. 3: Untitled, p. 34 (Box 98)
    - The International Review of African American Art, vol.16, no. 3: "The Temptation of Eve Revisited"; p. 20 (Box 98)
    - The International Review of African American Art, vol. 20, no. 3: "Picturing Us: Together" by Clarissa T. Sligh, p. 46 (Box 98)
    - The International Review of African American Art, vol. 21, no. 3: "Transforming Hate Literature With Origami" by Clarissa T. Sligh, p. 62 (Box 98)
    - The International Review of African American Art, vol. 22, no. 1: "Jake in Transition" and "Masculinity Project: Tommy with Roses"; p. 57 (Box 98)
    - The International Review of African American Art, vol 22, no. 4, 2009: "Wrongly Bodied"; pps. 59-61 (Box 98)
    - New Art Examiner, vol. 20, no. 8, April 1993: "The X Factor" by Darrell Moore; pps. 18-22 (Box 98)
    - NKA: Journal of Contemporary African Art, no. 3, Fall/Winter 1995: Portfolio; pps. 22-25 (Box 98)
    - Orator: Smithsonian Institute--National African American Museum Project, vol. 2, no. 1, Spring 1994: "(Re)union: Artist Clarissa T. Sligh Finds her Family" by Jane Lusaka; pps. 5-11 (Box 98)
    - Positions, vol. 1, no. 1, 1989: "What's Happening With Momma" and "Assurance of Silence"; pps. 38-39 (Box 98)
    - Potomac Review, issue 38, Fall/Winter 2004-05: "It Wasn't Little Rock" by Clarissa T. Sligh; pps. 7-25 (Box 98)
    - Ten.8 (Critical Decade), vol. 2, no. 3, Spring 1992: "Mississippi is America" and "She Slept with Her Brother"; p. 104-105 (Box 98)
    - Upfront, Winter 1983-84: "This is a Political Document: A Description of the Making of a Work of Art"; pps. 13-17 (Box 98)
    - Upfront, no. 11, Winter 1985-86: Memorial to Aaron Roseman; p. 1 (Box 98)
    - Washington Project for the Arts, Summer 2001: Cover Art and Interview (p. 2) (Box 98)
    - The Witness, vol. 75, no. 12, December 1992: "Witness to Dissent", p. 31 (Box 98)
    - Women Artists News, vol. 13, no.3, Fall 1988: "Reframing the Past"; p. 27 (Box 98)
  - Jake in Transition (Box 99)
  - Mr. Burling's Chauffeur (Box 99)
  - Rata Lane and Diane Moonmade- Cafe in Soho - contact sheet (Box 99)
  - Exhibition Opening at VSW with Nancy Chalker-Tennant (Box 99)
  - Ellen Eisenman Portraits (3 folders) contact sheets (Box 99)
  - Deb Photographing Sligh in Arlington - contact sheet (Box 99)
  - Protest and Survive! (Box 100)
  - Photographing Jake's Female to Male Process (Box 100)
  - X Amount of Time (Box 100)
  - Sharp Rocks (Box 100)
  - Attica Book (Box 100)
  - Reframing the White Man's Bible (Box 101)
  - It Wasn't Little Rock booklet (Box 101)
  - What's Happening With Momma? (Text/Stair samples) (Box 101)
  - The Proposal (booklet) (Box 101)
  - The Journey (Box 101)
  - It Wasn't Little Rock (Box 101)
  - Exhibition Prints of Clarissa Sligh (Box 101)
  - Photograph of Clarissa Sligh (Box 101)
  - Published artists' books by other authors including works from Nexus Press, Women's Studio Workshop, and the artist Margot Lovejoy (Box 102)
  - Masculinity Project Part 1 of 2 (8x10 black and white prints) (Box 103)
  - Masculinity Project Part 2 of 2 (8x10 black and white prints) (Box 103)
  - Masculinity Project Part 1 of 3 (11x14 black and white prints) (Box 103)